JULIAN VAN OST

Sunnyvale, CA | Phone: 714-336-6230 | Email: julianvanost@gmail.com LinkedIn | Web Portfolio | Github

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer specialized in Front End and UI/UX Design and Development. Effective at harnessing creativity to create solutions for project requirements while also keeping applications enjoyable and engaging. Collaborative and helpful personality with a desire to constantly progress.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, VBA, SQL, MongoDB, Node.js, React.js, Handlebars, jQuery, Express.js,

Axios, AJAX, MERN. JSX, JAWS

Applications: Visual Studio Code, Git, Subversion, Brackets, Sublime, Bash, Terminal, Windows and Mac.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Web Developer & Lead Application Engineer Silberman Law Offices, LLP

2019 - Present Orange, CA

- Developing and perfecting previously bespoke file management and accounting program solutions using
- VBA and associated libraries to improve functionality and increase marketability of the program.
- MS Access functionality improvements including application integration with MS Office Suite.
- Creating and implemented new program functions including: ability to create calendar events
 directly from Access into MS Outlook calendar; automated creation of self-populating Word templates
 from SQL strings within the database; and adding custom signatures per user on each signed report
 using bitmaps.
- User training on new and improved functionality with constant and direct feedback from users to streamline functionality and improve user experience to fit the needs of the end user.
- Working with firm partners to develop creative solutions for any design requirements, such as a new business logo and color palettes to be implemented throughout the firm's recent re-branding and for use on their website, business cards, letterheads, and more.

Freelance Web Developer Self Employed

2018 - Present Sunnyvale, CA

- Freelance Development & I.T. Solutions
- Created customized websites for companies and individuals.
- Designed, built, and maintained websites for small businesses utilizing direct communication to provide support for web hosting, domain maintenance, and DNS migration.

Front End Web Developer - UI/UX Exterro. Inc.

2015 - 2018 Portland, Oregon

• Worked with a small local team to design, prototype and develop the front end of a suite of web applications for a legal technology company.

- Distilling complex problems into smaller and manageable tasks in order to handle difficult requirements.
- Collaborated with a larger international team of developers in order to fulfil backend application requirements.
- Troubleshooting, bug fixes, code review, and refactoring were regularly assigned.
- Frequent communication with Project Managers in order to figure out the stress points of the application in order to redesign or refactor existing modules in the product.

RECENT PROJECTS

Web Portfolio | Live Deployed Application | GitHub Repository

- Responsibilities: Ground-up design and creation of web portfolio project including customization of Bootstrap is components to work properly with a React is framework website. Created a brief portfolio outlining my experience and included links to recent project.
- **Technologies:** JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React.is, JSX, node.is, Bootstrap.is,

Crypit | Live Deployed Application | GitHub Repository

A simple API based comparison and watch list application to compare current stock and crypto currency prices.

- Responsibilities: Building the front end of the application and completing the look and feel using CSS and DOM manipulation with JS.
- **Technologies:** JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, and AJAX requests from external APIs.

Ambutrack | Live Deployed Application | GitHub Repository

A full-stack web application that helps first responders (specifically paramedics) log their calls, hours, and other data in a database.

- Responsibilities: Front-End DOM manipulation, view navigation, design and logo creation, wireframing and UI/UX of the entire application.
- Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, React-DOM-Views, Sequelize, MySQL, JAWS DB, JSX, Express.js.

Cartner Golf I Live Deployed Application I GitHub Repository

A full-stack web application that allows users to create accounts with a secure salted hash password stored in a Mongo database. Friend requests send and receive capabilities and ability to create golf matches with friends.

- Responsibilities: Building React Views and application functionality. Creating routes and styling with the Materialize framework. Polishing application features with CSS and Materialize class overrides. Creation of design and logos used in application and then implementation of those.
- Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React, Materialize, Mongoose, Mlab, MongoDB, JSX, Express.js, Axios, Concurrently, Passport, JSON Web Tokens

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Flex Web Development University of California Irvine

2020 - 2020 Irvine, CA

A full time, three-month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.js.

UCI Bootcamp Verified Certificate

Computer Science - A.S. Irvine Valley College

2012 - 2015 Irvine. CA

Attended Irvine Valley College and took every computer science class they had to offer at the time. 74.50 Total Credits Earned and 9 Computer Science Credits Earned.